<title>Spicy Maple Bacon Wrapped Shrimp</title>
<time_min>50</time_min>
<servings>5</servings>
<source>https://www.inspiredtaste.net/15948/spicy-maple-bacon-wrapped-shrimp-recipe/</source>
<tags>
	<tag>fish</tag>
</tags>

<ingredients_list>
<list_title></list_title>
	<ingredient>
		<name>bacon</name>
		<amount>10</amount>
		<unit>pieces</unit>
		<note>thin cut strips</note>
	</ingredient>
	<ingredient>
		<name>shrimp</name>
		<amount>20</amount>
		<unit>pieces</unit>
		<note>extra-large, shelled with tails left on (about 1 pound)</note>
	</ingredient>
	<ingredient>
		<name>salt</name>
		<amount>0.25</amount>
		<unit>teaspoon</unit>
		<note>kosher</note>
	</ingredient>
	<ingredient>
		<name>maple syrup</name>
		<amount>2</amount>
		<unit>tablespoons</unit>
		<note></note>
	</ingredient>
<list_title></list_title>
	<ingredient>
		<name>hot chili sauce</name>
		<amount>1</amount>
		<unit>tablespoon</unit>
		<note>Sriracha or other</note>
	</ingredient>
	<ingredient>
		<name>lemon</name>
		<amount>0.5</amount>
		<unit>pieces</unit>
		<note>cut into wedges, for serving</note>
	</ingredient>
	<ingredient>
		<name>scallion</name>
		<amount>1</amount>
		<unit>piece</unit>
		<note>finely chopped, for serving</note>
	</ingredient>
</ingredients_list>

<directions>
	<step>Prepare Bacon: 

Heat oven to 400 degrees F. Line a large baking sheet with aluminum foil.

Place bacon slices, in one layer, onto the baking sheet. Slide into the oven, and then bake about 10 minutes or until the bacon has rendered some of its fat, is starting to brown on the edges, but is still floppy. Take the bacon out of the oven and transfer to paper towels to drain excess fat. Discard any fat on the baking sheet, but leave the foil intact.
	</step>
	<step>Glaze Shrimp and Bacon: 

Stir the maple syrup and Sriracha in a small bowl. Lightly brush both sides of the par-cooked bacon with glaze, and then cut in half, crosswise, making 20 half-strips of bacon.

Season the shrimp with salt then wrap each shrimp with a half-strip of bacon and use one of the soaked skewers to secure it.
	</step>
	<step>Bake Shrimp: 

Place each shrimp onto the baking sheet. Then brush or spoon leftover glaze over wrapped shrimp.

Bake the shrimp for 5 minutes. Turn the oven to broil, and then broil 4 to 6 minutes, rotating the shrimp once, until the bacon is crispy. Serve shrimp with lemon wedges on the side and scallions scattered on top.
	</step>
</directions>
